<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on </title>
    <link>/tags/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 22:21:06 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nile River Dispute between Ethopia, Sudan and Egypt</title>
      <link>/news/2019-11-08-nile-rive-dispute/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 22:21:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2019-11-08-nile-rive-dispute/</guid>
      <description>One of the finest story I have ever read it titled &amp;ldquo; I Dared My Best Friend to Ruin My Life - He&amp;rsquo;s Succeeding&amp;rdquo; and can be read here. This 8 part series takes you down a chilling ride of shock and horror. So lifelike is the authors potrayal of the story that you could feel it happening at that very moment. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read it before, it is highly recommended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nile River Dispute between Ethopia, Sudan and Egypt</title>
      <link>/post/2019-11-08-nile-rive-dispute/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 22:21:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-11-08-nile-rive-dispute/</guid>
      <description>It all started with one news article here and I went down a rabbit hole as to what is this Nile dispute all about. Political news, crisis reports, few wikipedia sources and I landed up this page. Now, wait. This gets interesting. I have seen this guy before on Twitter and that too very recently. I was right! It&amp;rsquo;s right in the second paragraph of the page. He was the Nobel Peace Prize recipient for 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Blog Post</title>
      <link>/post/2019-03-18-first-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-03-18-first-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>Get it from github. See the live demo. See it in action on my own blog.  Welcome to the sample post for the Jekyll Clean theme.
A simple and clean Jekyll theme using bootstrap (not to be confused with jekyll-bootstrap) that&amp;rsquo;s easy to modify and very modular in component and element reuse.
It uses Disqus for comments and includes Google Analytics support. Both of these features are disabled by default and can be enabled via _config.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>